suppose that the > of 2 is rational so
there exist positive integers A and B
with a^2 equal to 2 b^2 that means that
we have an a by a square that has the
same area as 2 B by B squares according
to the carpet's theorem if we overlay
the 2 B by B squares into the a by a
square since the areas are equal we must
have that the area of overlap which is a
2 b - A by 2 b - a square is equal to
the uncovered area in the a by a square
which is 2 Aus B by A- B squares but
this means that the quantity 2 b - A 2
is equal to 2 * the quantity a - b^ 2 so
we've produced a pair of smaller
positive integers satisfying the same
equation x^2 = 2 y^2 we can repeat this
process over and over again producing a
list of smaller and smaller positive
integers but such an infinite list of
decreasing positive integers can't exist
so we've produced a contradiction this
means that a squ can't equal 2 b^ s with
A and B integers so the square root of
two is irrational